Mss.Ms.Coll.97
American Philosophical Society
- I. Correspondence, 1929-1997; 3.5 Linear feet (Box 1-7)
  - Luciers, F., 1943 (Box 4)
    Pacifique, Reverend Father; Monastere des Freres-Mineurs Capucins
  - Luders, Ulrich, 1993; 2.0 Item(s) (Box 4)
    Lincom Europa
  - Ludwig, Andrea O., 1976; 3.0 Item(s) (Box 4)
  - Lunkenheimer, Glenna and Paul, 1985; 1.0 Item(s) (Box 4)
  - MacDonnell, Thomas P., 1975-1994; 7.0 Item(s) (Box 4)
  - Maggs Brothers Limited, 1945; 1.0 Item(s) (Box 4)
  - Maine Indian Tribal-State Commission, 1991; 1.0 Item(s) (Box 4)
  - Maniuel, Martine, 1989; 1.0 Item(s) (Box 4)
  - Mason, J. Alden, 1934; 1.0 Item(s) (Box 4)
    University Museum, University of Pennsylvania
  - Masthay, Carl, 1979-1991, n.d.; 22.0 Item(s) (Box 4)
  - Mathias, James F., 1970; 2.0 Item(s) (Box 4)
  - McCorison, Marcus A., 1988-1994; 2.0 Item(s) (Box 4)
    American Antiquarian Society; Christie, Manson, and Woods International
  - McEllroy, W. S., 1956; 1.0 Item(s) (Box 4)
    Letter written to Albert Craig
  - McKeough, Helen M., 1981-1996, n.d.; 15.0 Item(s) (Box 4)
  - McKinstry, H. E., 1937; 1.0 Item(s) (Box 4)
  - McKrae, Jill F. Kealey, 1994-1995; 3.0 Item(s) (Box 4)
  - Meade, Edward J., Jr., 1983; 1.0 Item(s) (Box 4)
    Ford Foundation
  - Meldrum, W. B. (William Buell), 1942; 1.0 Item(s) (Box 4)
  - Merrell, James H., 1981-1982; 7.0 Item(s) (Box 4)
  - [Meyer], Heidi, 1964; 1.0 Item(s) (Box 4)
  - Michelson, Truman, 1934-1938; 11.0 Item(s) (Box 4)
  - Micmac-Maliseet Institute, 1991; 1.0 Item(s) (Box 4)
  - Middleton, Dorothy E., 1932; 1.0 Item(s) (Box 4)
  - Millar, Eric G., 1933; 4.0 Item(s) (Box 4)
  - Miller, P. Schuyler, 1968; 9.0 Item(s) (Box 4)
  - Mills, Elaine L., 1986-1990; 4.0 Item(s) (Box 4)
  - Mitchell, Francis D., 1989; 2.0 Item(s) (Box 4)
  - Mitchell, George W., Jr., 1988-1989; 5.0 Item(s) (Box 4)
    Penobscot Cultural Center; Seeber, Pauline
  - Monahan, Barbara, 1990; 1.0 Item(s) (Box 5)
    Piscataquis Regional Young Men's Christian Association
  - Monke, Ingrid, 1989; 1.0 Item(s) (Box 5)
    Maine Humanities Council
  - Moody, John, n.d.; 1.0 Item(s) (Box 5)
  - Moore, Robert M., 1938; 1.0 Item(s) (Box 5)
  - Moorehead, Warren King, 1987; 2.0 Item(s) (Box 5)
  - Morgan, Lael, 1984; 2.0 Item(s) (Box 5)
  - Morley, Felix, 1941; 1.0 Item(s) (Box 5)
  - Moulton, F. R. (Forest Ray), 1938; 2.0 Item(s) (Box 5)
    American Association for the Advancement of Science
  - Murphy, Richard M., 1981; 1.0 Item(s) (Box 5)
    National Endowment for the Humanities
  - Myers, Albert Cook, 1932; 3.0 Item(s) (Box 5)
    Commemoration of the 250th Anniversary of William Penn in America
  - National Endowment for the Humanities, 1981; 4.0 Item(s) (Box 5)
  - New England Historic Genealogical Society Library, 1988; 1.0 Item(s) (Box 5)
  - New York Public Library, Reserve Division, 1988; 1.0 Item(s) (Box 5)
  - Newmeyer, Frederick J., 1990; 2.0 Item(s) (Box 5)
  - Nicholas, Andrea Bear, 1983-1986; 5.0 Item(s) (Box 5)
  - Norman, Jean, 1967; 2.0 Item(s) (Box 5)
    University of Toronto Press
  - Nurmekund, Pent, 1995; 1.0 Item(s) (Box 5)
    Letter to Robert J. Throckmorton
  - Nye, Gerald P., 1939; 3.0 Item(s) (Box 5)
  - O'Donnell, Mathew Pierce, 1987; 1.0 Item(s) (Box 5)
  - Old Town Museum, 1995; 6.0 p. (Box 5)
    Siebert Basket Display, June 1995
  - Olmstead, D. L., 1972; 1.0 Item(s) (Box 5)
  - Olsen, E. T., 1939-1940; 5.0 Item(s) (Box 5)
    State University and Crippled Children's Hospitals, Oklahoma
  - O'Meara, John, 1995; 1.0 Item(s) (Box 5)
    Letter to Carl [Mathay]. Includes English-Native American vocabulary
  - Orchard, W. C. (William C.), 1936; 1.0 Item(s) (Box 5)
  - Ortlepp, William H., 1979; 1.0 Item(s) (Box 5)
  - Pacifique, Reverend Father, 1938-1940; 9.0 Item(s) (Box 5)
    Monastere des Freres-Mineurs Capucins
  - Palmer, Ralph S., 1965; 1.0 Item(s) (Box 5)
  - Pare, Rick and Nancy, 1989; 1.0 Item(s) (Box 5)
  - Parkinson, A. D., 1936; 1.0 Item(s) (Box 5)
    Jones, Daniel; University of London, University College
  - Parks, Doug, 1996; 1.0 Item(s) (Box 5)
  - Parks, Lucy, 1936; 1.0 Item(s) (Box 5)
  - Parks, Ruth, 1936; 1.0 Item(s) (Box 5)
  - Peacock, James L., 1993; 3.0 Item(s) (Box 5)
    John Simon Guggenheim Memorial Foundation
  - Pendergast, Jim, 1983; 1.0 Item(s) (Box 5)
  - Penobscot Nation, 1979-1986, n.d.; 12.0 Item(s) (Box 5)
  - Pepper, O. H. Perry, 1939; 1.0 Item(s) (Box 5)
    Hospital of the University of Pennsylvania
  - Pepper, William, 1934-1937; 7.0 Item(s) (Box 5)
    University of Pennsylvania, School of Medicine
  - Peters, Nick, 1938; 3.0 Item(s) (Box 5)
  - Petersen, James B., 1995-1996; 14.0 Item(s) (Box 5)
  - Petry, H. K., 1939; 3.0 Item(s) (Box 5)
    Commonwealth of Pennsylvania, Department of Welfare
  - Plain Truth, 1984; 1.0 Item(s) (Box 5)
    Bauer, Ted
  - [Pontius], Mary, 1939; 1.0 Item(s) (Box 5)
  - Pratt, Anne S., 1931; 2.0 Item(s) (Box 5)
    Yale University Library
  - Prins, Harald, 1988-1996; 3.0 Item(s) (Box 5)
  - Proulx, Paul, 1976-1982, n.d.; 7.0 Item(s) (Box 5)
  - Quadrangle, 1985-1987; 2.0 Item(s) (Box 5)
    Maxfield, William; Haverford College
  - Quarterly Progress Report, 1988; 1.0 Item(s) (Box 5)
    Penobscot Cultural Center
  - Quinn, Catherine C., 1933; 2.0 Item(s) (Box 5)
    John Carter Brown Library
  - Quinn, Conor McDonough, 1996, n.d.; 2.0 Item(s) (Box 5)
    One letter is written in the Penobscot language
  - Rankin, Nancy, 1986-1988; 2.0 Item(s) (Box 5)
  - Rankin, Robert L., 1993; 1.0 Item(s) (Box 5)
  - Ray, Gordon N., 1969-1985; 17.0 Item(s) (Box 5)
  - Ray, Roger B., 1996; 1.0 Item(s) (Box 5)
  - Reading Hospital, 1940; 1.0 Item(s) (Box 5)
  - Reese, Lewis L., 1940; 1.0 Item(s) (Box 5)
    University Hospitals, Oklahoma
  - Reid, 1932; 1.0 Item(s) (Box 5)
    Cousin Reid
  - [Reid, L. W.], 1944; 1.0 Item(s) (Box 5)
    Phi Beta Kappa, Haverford College
  - Rementer, Jim, 1985; 4.0 Item(s) (Box 5)
  - Reynolds, Margaret W., 1987; 1.0 Item(s) (Box 5)
  - Rhine, Mary, 1989; 1.0 Item(s) (Box 5)
  - Rhodes, Richard, 1985; 1.0 Item(s) (Box 5)
  - Richardson, Hubbard, 1978-1989; 2.0 Item(s) (Box 5)
  - Ritchie, William A., 1934; 2.0 Item(s) (Box 5)
    New York State Archaeological Association
  - Roberts, Ethel D., 1933; 1.0 Item(s) (Box 5)
    Wellesley College Library
  - Robinson, Cedrick L. ("Rob"), 1973-1974; 2.0 Item(s) (Box 5)
  - Rogers, Jean, 1975; 2.0 Item(s) (Box 5)
  - Romanoff, Stephen J., 1979 (Box 5)
  - Rood, David S., 1980-1992; 16.0 Item(s) (Box 5)
    International Journal of American Linguistics; Proulx, Paul
  - [Rorico], Valentine, 1935; 1.0 Item(s) (Box 5)
  - Ross, Adeline, 1937; 1.0 Item(s) (Box 5)
    St. Michael Mission
  - Roth, John E., 1986; 3.0 Item(s) (Box 5)
  - Rothenheber, Paul, 1993; 1.0 Item(s) (Box 5)
    High-Tech Educational Services, Bismarck, ND
  - Rountree, Helen C., 1995; 3.0 Item(s) (Box 5)
  - Roy, 1994; 1.0 Item(s) (Box 5)
  - Rudes, Blair, 1995; 1.0 Item(s) (Box 5)
  - Ruhlen, Merritt, 1994; 3.0 Item(s) (Box 5)
  - Russell, Mary E., 1989; 1.0 Item(s) (Box 5)
  - Ryan and Christie Storage, Inc., 1986; 3.0 Item(s) (Box 5)
  - St. John, Robin, 1971; 1.0 Item(s) (Box 5)
  - Salisbury, Neal, 1970; 1.0 Item(s) (Box 5)
  - Sally, 1945; 1.0 Item(s) (Box 5)
  - Salzman, Zdenek, 1964; 1.0 Item(s) (Box 5)
  - Sands, Donald, 1983-1984; 3.0 Item(s) (Box 5)
  - Saphir, Otto, 1941; 1.0 Item(s) (Box 5)
    Michael Reese Hospital, Chicago, IL
  - Sapiel, Francis C. (Bobcat), 1981; 1.0 Item(s) (Box 5)
    Penobscot National Historical Society
  - Sappier, James G., 1990; 1.0 Item(s) (Box 5)
    Penobscot Cultural Center and Museum
  - Saul, C. Dudley, 1942; 1.0 Item(s) (Box 5)
    St. Luke's and Children's Medical Center, Philadelphia, PA
  - Scancarelli, Janine, 1987-1994; 3.0 Item(s) (Box 6)
  - Schenken, Jerald R., 1987; 1.0 p. (Box 6)
  - Schmuckie, Louis and Marcie, 1986-1995; 4.0 Item(s) (Box 6)
  - Schwartz, Dorothy, 1989; 1.0 Item(s) (Box 6)
  - Schwarze, W. U., 1932; 1.0 Item(s) (Box 6)
    Moravian College and Theological Seminary
  - Sebeok, Thomas A., 1973; 1.0 Item(s) (Box 6)
  - Seeber, Pauleena M., 1986-1988; 17.0 Item(s) (Box 6)
    Penobscot Nation, Department of Humanities
  - Shappell, Betty, 1939; 1.0 Item(s) (Box 6)
  - Shaw, John J., 1938; 1.0 Item(s) (Box 6)
    Commonwealth of Pennsylvania, Department of Health
  - Sheets, Ossie and Elsie, 1962-1965; 2.0 Item(s) (Box 6)
  - Shipley, William and Nancy Rankin, 1989; 1.0 Item(s) (Box 6)
  - Sholes, S., 1935; 8.0 Item(s) (Box 6)
    Presto Recording Corporation
  - Shryock, Richard H., 1961-1963; 4.0 Item(s) (Box 6)
  - Siebert, Carol, 1987; 1.0 Item(s) (Box 6)
  - Siebert, Florence, 1974-1996; 5.0 Item(s) (Box 6)
  - Siebert, George, 1987-1996; 4.0 Item(s) (Box 6)
  - Siebert, Lillie, 1933; 1.0 Item(s) (Box 6)
    Letter to Lillie Siebert from Friedrich WIlhelms Universitat, Berlin, Germany. In German
  - Siebert, Marion (Mrs. Frank), 1960; 2.0 Item(s) (Box 6)
  - Siebert, Peggy, 1979-1996; 3.0 Item(s) (Box 6)
  - Siebert, Sally, 1986-1996; 2.0 Item(s) (Box 6)
  - Sieceichowicz, Krystyna, 1996; 1.0 Item(s) (Box 6)
  - Silverstein, Michael, 1984-1986; 4.0 Item(s) (Box 6)
  - Singer, Richard B. and Margaret, 1980-1993; 10.0 Item(s) (Box 6)
  - Sloper, J. C., 1958-1959; 2.0 Item(s) (Box 6)
  - Smith, Linda, 1985; 1.0 Item(s) (Box 6)
  - Smith, Marian W., 1942; 1.0 Item(s) (Box 6)
  - Smith, Nicholas N., 1989-1996; 7.0 Item(s) (Box 6)
  - Smith, Peter, 1930; 1.0 Item(s) (Box 6)
    National Bibliophile Service
  - Smith-Breckling, Carol B., 1980-1996; 13.0 Item(s) (Box 6)
  - Smithsonian Institution, Department of Humanities, 1986; 1.0 Item(s) (Box 6)
  - Snider, Gordon L., 1958-1959; 2.0 Item(s) (Box 6)
  - Snow, Dean R., 1970-1972; 2.0 Item(s) (Box 6)
  - Snowe, Olympia, 1981; 1.0 Item(s) (Box 6)
    United States House of Representatives
  - Snyder, Audrey, 1994; 1.0 Item(s) (Box 6)
  - Snyder, Heinrick, 1992; 1.0 Item(s) (Box 6)
  - Sobczak, J., 1975; 1.0 Item(s) (Box 6)
    College of American Pathologists
  - Society for Pennsylvania Archaeology, 1947-1949; 6.0 Item(s) (Box 6)
  - Society for the Study of Indigenous Languages, 1.0 Item(s) (Box 6)
  - Spang, Bruce, 1980, n.d.; 2.0 Item(s) (Box 6)
  - Spannuth, John R., 1939; 1.0 Item(s) (Box 6)
  - Speck, Frank, 1938-1940; 8.0 Item(s) (Box 6)
  - Stacey Koon Defense Fund, 1.0 Item(s) (Box 6)
  - Stanislaus, Francis, 1936-1938; 3.0 Item(s) (Box 6)
  - Stewart, Alice R., 1983; 1.0 Item(s) (Box 6)
  - Storm, Colton, 1944; 2.0 Item(s) (Box 6)
  - Streeter, Thomas W., 1956; 1.0 Item(s) (Box 6)
  - Struever, Stuart, 1969; 1.0 Item(s) (Box 6)
  - Stuart, Judi and Jack, 1971, n.d.; 2.0 Item(s) (Box 6)
  - Studenski, E. R., 1957; 1.0 Item(s) (Box 6)
  - Sturgis, Cyrus C., 1938-1940; 3.0 Item(s) (Box 6)
    University of Michigan, University Hospital
  - Sturtevant, William C., 1957-1987; 6.0 Item(s) (Box 6)
  - Sudak, Alexander, 1989; 2.0 Item(s) (Box 6)
  - Swanton, John R., 1940; 1.0 Item(s) (Box 6)
  - Taft, Robert A., 1939; 1.0 Item(s) (Box 6)
  - Tatem, William, 1988-1996; 10.0 Item(s) (Box 6)
  - Taukchiray, Wes, 1991-1997, n.d.; 4.0 folders (Box 6)
    Correspondence related to Catawba. See also, Series I: White, Wes
    - Folder #1, 1991-1992 (Box 6)
    - Folder #2, 1993 (Box 6)
    - Folder #3, 1994-1997 (Box 6)
    - Folder #4, n.d. (Box 6)
  - Tax, Sol, 1968; 1.0 Item(s) (Box 6)
    Current Anthropology
  - Taylor, Allan R., 1972-1973; 4.0 Item(s) (Box 6)
  - Ted, 1992; 1.0 Item(s) (Box 6)
  - Teeter, Karl V., 1967; 1.0 Item(s) (Box 6)
  - Thomas, Gladys (Mrs. Howard), 1954; 1.0 Item(s) (Box 6)
  - Thomas, Robert G., 1977; 1.0 Item(s) (Box 6)
    Private Practitioners of Pathology Foundation
  - Thomason, Sarah G., 1989-1994, n.d.; 6.0 Item(s) (Box 6)
  - Thompson, Ann and Bryan, 1994; 1.0 Item(s) (Box 6)
  - Thompson, Theresa E., 1987; 1.0 Item(s) (Box 6)
  - Thomson, Robert C., 1939; 1.0 Item(s) (Box 6)
  - Todd, Evelyn, 1972; 1.0 Item(s) (Box 7)
  - Trager, George L., 1937; 1.0 Item(s) (Box 7)
  - Traugott, Elizabeth C., 1988; 1.0 Item(s) (Box 7)
  - Trimnal, Roger S., [1990]; 1.0 Item(s) (Box 7)
    Catawba Cultural Preservation Project
  - Tufts, Alyson, 1986; 1.0 Item(s) (Box 7)
    Edward W. Hazen Foundation
  - Tully, Melba W., 1953-1996; 24.0 Item(s) (Box 7)
  - Tuttle, Edward F., 1975; 3.0 Item(s) (Box 7)
    See also Series VII: Tuttle, Edward. Borrowing Versus Semantic Shift...
  - Tzhe, Ben and Helen, 1973; 1.0 Item(s) (Box 7)
  - Uhlenbeck, C. C. (Christianus Cornelius), 1938; 1.0 Item(s) (Box 7)
  - Unami Lodge, 1932; 3.0 Item(s) (Box 7)
    Philadelphia Council, Boy Scouts of America
  - Uncle Joe, 1939; 1.0 Item(s) (Box 7)
  - UNITISC, 1996; 1.0 Item(s) (Box 7)
    Ryan and Christie Storage, Inc.
  - Unknown, 1938-1996; 2.0 Item(s) (Box 7)
  - Ury, Randy, 1.0 Item(s) (Box 7)
  - Vail, R. W. G. (Robert William Glenroie), 1943-1944; 3.0 Item(s) (Box 7)
    University of the State of New York, New York State Library
  - Vandenberg, Arthur H., 1939; 1.0 Item(s) (Box 7)
  - VanNuys, John D., 1940-1941; 2.0 Item(s) (Box 7)
    Indiana University Medical Center
  - Veale, Y. V., 1930-1931; 2.0 Item(s) (Box 7)
  - Vennum, Thomas, Jr., 1988; 1.0 Item(s) (Box 7)
  - Voorhis, Paul, 1984; 2.0 Item(s) (Box 7)
  - Walker, Willard, 1967-1995; 4.0 Item(s) (Box 7)
  - Warne, Janet, 1977; 2.0 Item(s) (Box 7)
  - Washburn, Wilcomb E., 1972-1974; 6.0 Item(s) (Box 7)
  - Wasson, H. Carl, 1959; 1.0 Item(s) (Box 7)
  - Wasson, Lois (Mrs. H. Carl), [1952]-1958, n.d.; 3.0 Item(s) (Box 7)
  - Wenzel, Beth, 1949; 1.0 Item(s) (Box 7)
  - Wetmore, R. Y., 1980; 1.0 Item(s) (Box 7)
    St. Andrews Presbyterian College
  - Weyl, Nathaniel, 1991; 3.0 Item(s) (Box 7)
  - Whipple, G. H. (George Hoyt), 1941; 1.0 Item(s) (Box 7)
    University of Rochester, School of Medicine and Dentistry
  - White, Wes, 1987; 2.0 Item(s) (Box 7)
    See also, Series I: Taukchiray, Wes
  - Whitney, Alvin G., 1933; 2.0 Item(s) (Box 7)
    New York State Museum
  - Whorf, Ben L., 1938-1940; 2.0 Item(s) (Box 7)
  - Wilkins, A. E., 1933; 1.0 Item(s) (Box 7)
    Gloucester County Historical Society
  - Willey, Laurence N., 1989; 1.0 Item(s) (Box 7)
  - Williams, Lorraine E., 1974; 2.0 Item(s) (Box 7)
    New Jersey State Museum, Bureau of Archaeology
  - Williams, Tom E., 1940; 1.0 Item(s) (Box 7)
  - Wilson, Sherilyn, 1985; 1.0 Item(s) (Box 7)
  - Witherell, Elizabeth, 1983; 1.0 Item(s) (Box 7)
    Writings of Henry David Thoreau
  - Wolf, Edwin, 1969; 1.0 Item(s) (Box 7)
    Library Company of Philadelphia
  - Wolfart, H. Christoph, 1988; 1.0 Item(s) (Box 7)
  - Wright, Harry A., 1939; 3.0 Item(s) (Box 7)
  - Wykoff, M. William, 1977-1994; 13.0 Item(s) (Box 7)
  - Yale University Library, 1931; 1.0 Item(s) (Box 7)
    Torn letter fragment
  - Young, Martha, 1996; 1.0 Item(s) (Box 7)
    Letter to Douglas Parks
  - Zahn, Mabel, 1972-1973; 2.0 Item(s) (Box 7)
    Charles Sessler, Bookseller and Printseller
  - Zimmerman, H. M., 1941; 1.0 Item(s) (Box 7)
    Yale University, School of Medicine
  - Zinman, Michael, 1995, n.d.; 2.0 Item(s) (Box 7)
    Zinman signed one of the letters with a psedonym, "Candide" Zinman
- II. Catawba, 3.5 Linear feet (Box 8-14)
  - Indian Vocabulary from Fort Christanna, 1716, 1971; 16.0 p.; Alexander, Edward P., (Edward Porter), 1907-2003 (Box 8)
    Virginia Magazine of History and Biography, vol. 79, no. 3
  - Historic Catawba Peoples: Exploratory Perspectives in Ethnohistory and Arecheology, 1975; 4.0 p.; Baker, Steven G. (Box 8)
    Notes by Wes Taukchiray on working draft.
  - Correspondence and Papers of Benjamin S. Barton, H. S. P. Letter from John Drayton to Barton. 9 September 1803 [Catawba Vocabulary], 2.0 p.; Barton, Benjamin Smith, 1766-1815 (Box 8)
  - Bibliography for Catawba, n.d.; 12.0 p. (Box 8)
  - Catawba Influences on Modern Cherokee Pottery Tradition, 1987; 21.0 p.; Blumer, Thomas J., 1937- (Box 8)
    Appalachian Journal, vol. 14, no. 2
  - History as a Tool in Folklife Study of the Catawba Indians of South Carolina, 1983; 6.0 p.; Blumer, Thomas J., 1937- (Box 8)
    New York Folklore, Special Issue, Folklore: The State of the Field
  - [Three Catawba Subjects: Writings], 1985-1987; 3.0 p.; Blumer, Thomas J., 1937- (Box 8)
    A short journal article and two editorial letters
  - Wild Indians and the Devil: The Contemporary Catawba Indian Spirit World, 1985; 20.0 p.; Blumer, Thomas J., 1937- (Box 8)
    American Indian Quarterly, Spring 1985
  - Map, Probable Route Taken by John Lederer, 1987; 1.0 p.; Briceland, Alan Vance, 1939- (Box 8)
    Photocopy from Briceland's Westward from Virginia: The Exploration of the Virginia-Carolina Frontier (Charlottesville, 1987)
  - Recovery of the Catawbas, 1966; 14.0 p.; Brown, Douglas Summers (Box 8)
    Chapter from Brown's The Catawba Indians (University of South Carolina Press, 1966).
  - Brown, Margaret George (1838-1922), Circa 1900; 3.0 Item(s) (Box 8)
    - Margaret George Brown, 1838-1922, 1900
  - Catawba Census - Notes, 1830-1929, n.d. (Box 8)
  - Catawba Indian Language, R.C.A. Packing Slip, 1951; 1.0 p. (Box 8)
  - Catawba Introduction - Notes, n.d.; 3.0 p. (Box 8)
  - Catawba Land Claim Agreement, 1992-1993; 10.0 Item(s) (Box 8)
    Newspaper Clippings
  - Catawba Language - Frederick A. Porcher Family Papers, n.d.; 2.0 Item(s) (Box 8)
    Copies of original manuscripts held at the South Carolina Historical Society
  - Catawba Language - Oscar Montgomery Lieber Papers, 1856, n.d.; 13.0 p. (Box 8)
    Copies of original manuscripts held at the South Caroliniana Library
  - Catawba Language - Wesley D. White Collection, n.d.; 4.0 p. (Box 8)
  - Catawba Linguistic Notes, n.d.; 20.0 p. (Box 8)
  - Catawba Types, Places, Buildings, Crafts, n.d.; 5.0 p. (Box 8)
    Copies of photographs
  - [Catawba Vocabulary Notes], n.d.; 9.0 p. (Box 8)
  - Reminiscences of Charleston, 1854; 5.0 p.; Fraser, Charles, 1782-1860 (Box 8)
    Excerpt of 1969 reprint of 1854 work. Includes notes by Wes Taukchiray
  - Gordon, Sally Brown, n.d.; 2.0 p. (Box 8)
    Photocopies of photographs
  - Notes on Sewee Indians and Indian Remains of Christ Church Parish, Charleston County, South Carolina, 1925; 3.0 p.; Gregorie, Anne King (Box 8)
    Photocopy of title page, map, and one page of text only
  - Catawba, 1973; 24.0 p.; Hudson, Charles M. (Box 8)
    Chapter in The Southwest, Raymond Fogelson, ed.; vol. xiii of Handbook of North American Indians, William Sturtevant, ed. Includes annotations by Siebert dated May 1973.
  - Indian Wars in North Carolina, 1663-1763, 1963; 1.0 p.; Lee, Enoch Lawrence, 1912-1996 (Box 8)
    Title page only
  - Catawba Indian Music. The Truman Michelson Collection, 1986; 5.0 Item(s); Library of Congress (Box 8)
  - Notes on Wesley White's Report: The Waccamaws, 1982; 1.0 p.; Merrell, James Hart, 1953- (Box 8)
  - Reading An Almost Erased Page: A Reassessment of Frank G. Speck's Catawba Studies, 1983; 15.0 p.; Merrell, James Hart, 1953- (Box 8)
    Proceedings of the American Philosophical Society, vol. 127, no. 4. Annotated copy
  - Miscellaneous Notes and Maps. Catawba, 27.0 Item(s) (Box 8)
  - Letter to Albert Gatschet, 20 September 1887, n.d.; 2.0 p.; Mooney, James, 1861-1921 (Box 8)
    Photocopy. From Smithsonian manuscript #4047
  - James Mush, A Chickahominy Indian, 1704, 1993; 5.0 p. (Box 8)
    Printed excerpt from the Executive Journals of the Council of Colonial Virginia
  - Names in South Carolina, 1965; 3.0 Item(s) (Box 8)
  - Newspaper Clippings, 1976-1997 (Box 8)
    - Newspaper Clippings, 1976-1996; 7.0 Item(s) (Box 8)
    - Catawba Language Not Dead, Says Chief Blue, 1996; 1.0 p. (Box 8)
      CHerokee One Feather, January 24, 1996
    - Catawba Settlement Becomes State Law, 1993; 1.0 p. (Box 8)
      Robesonian, June 15, 1993
    - Future Arrives for Catawba Nation, 1993; 2.0 p.; Miller, Jeff (Box 8)
      The State, Columbia, SC
    - Red Thunder Chief Dies, Last Speaker of Catawba, 1996; 3.0 Item(s) (Box 8)
  - Nouns in Tutelo, 1992; 9.0 p.; Oliverio, Giulia R. M. (Box 8)
    Kansas Working Papers in Linguistics, vol. 17, no. 2
  - Loves of the Driver: A Story of the Wigwam, n.d.; 3.0 p.; Pendleton, P. C., (Philip C.) (Box 8)
    Excerpt from piece in The Magnolia, or Southern Monthly, vol. 3
  - Contributions to Catawba Ethnozoology, 1957; 5.0 p.; Pickens, Andrew Lee, 1890-1969 (Box 8)
  - Correspondence regarding Catawba, 1956-1957; 9.0 Item(s); Pickens, Andrew Lee, 1890-1969 (Box 8)
    Includes correspondence to and from Pickens and M. W. Stirling and Wlliam Sturtevant.
  - Natural History Articles on South Carolina, n.d.; 46.0 p.; Pickens, Andrew Lee, 1890-1969 (Box 8)
    Includes: Additions to the List of Birds of the Piedmont Region of South Carolina (The Auk, vol. XLV, no. 1, 1928); Birds of Upper South Carolina: A Study in Geographical Distribution (Wilson Bulletin, vol. XL, 1928); Mammals of Upper South Carolina (Journal of Mammology, vol. 9, no. 2, 1928); A List of the Vertebrates of Upper South Carolina
  - Recording the Catawba Language, 1928; 1.0 p. (Box 8)
    El Palacio, vol. 24. Refers to Frank G. Speck
  - Narratives of Early Carolina, 1650-1708 [excerpts], 1911; 9.0 p.; Salley, A. S., (Alexander Samuel), 1871-1961 (Box 8)
    Includes Henry Woodward, "A Faithful Relation of my Westoe Voiage," 1674
  - Catawba Lexicon, 1984; 4.0 folders; Shea, Kathleen (Box 9)
    Annotated manuscript copy of master's thesis, University of Kansas
  - Catawba Field Notes, 9.0 Volume(s); Siebert, Frank T. (Frank Thomas), 1912-1998 (Box 9)
    Notebook #1 missing.
    - Catawba Field Notes #2, n.d.; 50.0 p.; Siebert, Frank T. (Frank Thomas), 1912-1998 (Box 9)
    - Catawba Field Notes #3, n.d.; 51.0 p.; Siebert, Frank T. (Frank Thomas), 1912-1998 (Box 9)
    - Catawba Field Notes #4, n.d.; 19.0 p.; Siebert, Frank T. (Frank Thomas), 1912-1998 (Box 9)
      Includes Siebert's mother writing about Sally Brown Gordon
    - Catawba Field Notes #5, 1941; 82.0 p.; Siebert, Frank T. (Frank Thomas), 1912-1998 (Box 9)
      Notebook also labeled: "Book #3."
    - Catawba Field Notes #6, 1941; 44.0 p.; Siebert, Frank T. (Frank Thomas), 1912-1998 (Box 9)
      Notebook also labeled: "Book #4."
    - Catawba Field Notes #7, n.d.; 84.0 p.; Siebert, Frank T. (Frank Thomas), 1912-1998 (Box 9)
    - Catawba Field Notes #8. Notes on Catawba Grammar, n.d.; 59.0 p.; Siebert, Frank T. (Frank Thomas), 1912-1998 (Box 9)
    - Catawba Field Notes #9, n.d.; 104.0 p.; Siebert, Frank T. (Frank Thomas), 1912-1998 (Box 9)
    - Catawba Field Notes #10, n.d.; 240.0 p.; Siebert, Frank T. (Frank Thomas), 1912-1998 (Box 9)
  - Letter to William Sturtevant and Linguistic Notes, 1963; 6.0 p.; Siebert, Frank T. (Frank Thomas), 1912-1998 (Box 9)
  - Linguistic Classification of Catawba: Part I [annotated], 1945; 2.0 Item(s); Siebert, Frank T. (Frank Thomas), 1912-1998 (Box 9)
    International Journal of American Linguistics, vol. 11, no. 2. Two annotated copies
  - Linguistic Classifications of Catawba: PartI and Part II, 1945; 2.0 Item(s); Siebert, Frank T. (Frank Thomas), 1912-1998 (Box 9)
    Reprints from International Journal of American Linguistics: vol. 11, no. 2; vol. 11, no. 4
  - Research Notes, n.d.; 158.0 p.; Siebert, Frank T. (Frank Thomas), 1912-1998 (Box 10)
  - Research Notes - Catawba Vocabulary, Phonetics, Customs, 1941-1972, n.d.; 2.0 folders; Siebert, Frank T. (Frank Thomas), 1912-1998 (Box 10)
    - Folder #1. Bound Notebook, 1941, n.d.; 1.0 Volume(s); Siebert, Frank T. (Frank Thomas), 1912-1998 (Box 10)
    - Folder #2, 1972, n.d.; 27.0 p.; Siebert, Frank T. (Frank Thomas), 1912-1998 (Box 10)
      Loose papers found randomly inserted into bound volume (folder #1).
  - Rock Hill, South Carolina (Catawba Indian Reservation), 1940; 4.0 p; South Carolina Economic Association. (Box 10)
  - South Carolina Historical Magazine, 1995; 10.0 p. (Box 10)